Ralph Dugue

(201) 503-4408, rdugue1@gmail.com, https://www.linkedin.com/in/rdugue, https://ralphdugue.com/

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Software engineer with over 10 years of experience doing full-stack mobile and web development for small to medium, fast growing businesses. Passionate about creating clean and intuitive user interfaces, with a focus on accessibility for all users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Kotlin, Java, JavaScript, Typescript, Python, SQL, GraphQL

Frameworks: Android, Ktor, Vuejs, Spring, Apollo, Retrofit **Tools:** Android Studio, AWS, GCP, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Jira

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer / Writer - Self-Employed, Remote — JAN 2023 - PRESENT

- Published several articles on varying software engineering topics.
- Developed and released a parking assistance app, that utilizes Google
 ML Kit, Gemini Pro through Google Al studio and Kotlin Multiplatform
- Received a machine learning specialization through deep learning.ai and Stafford University.
- Participated in Kaggle competitions with newly acquired machine learning skills.

Mobile Engineer - ActiveCampaign, LLC, Remote — MAR 2021 - OCT 2022

- Improved the accessibility of the CRM mobile application, by updating the login screen to work more effectively with Android Voice Access, using Jetpack Compose.
- Grew Android user base and improved app store review score by developing features to increase parity with the web application using MVI, and Clean Architecture.
- Eliminated bugs, reduced boilerplate code, and addressed long standing technical debt by updating the mobile CRM application to use Dagger Hilt for dependency injection.
- Lead on refactoring the data-layer of the mobile CRM application to follow Clean
 Architecture and repository pattern more closely using Retrofit for network calls and
 Room/SQLDelight for local caching.
- Managed production release of new versions of the Android application to new users using Gitlab, AWS and Firebase.

Android Engineer - FanReach, LLC, Remote — APRIL 2018 - FEB 2021

- Lead on transitioning the Android code base to being Kotlin first, leading to quicker development and more modern Android architectural practices.
- Developed a "white label" platform to build and maintain several Android applications for professional sports organizations and venues, using Kotlin and MVVM.
- Developed video and audio media players to Allow users to watch live sporting events and highlights, using ExoPlayer Android library.
- Developed a chat client powered by AI, that is integrated in several apps using Kotlin and coroutines.
- Developed an events calendar that is integrated into several apps.

- Developed my professional website to host portfolio projects and blog content using Nuxt and NetlifyCMS.
- Created content on several tech / engineering topics.
- Consulted with several clients on leveraging serverless architectures through AWS Lambda and API Gateway as application backends.
- Developed MVP Vue.js human resources application.

Software Developer - Telco Equipment & Support Services, Remote — AUGUST 2013 - MARCH 2017

- Developed several proof-of-concept applications to demonstrate the viability of Android as an electronic resource planning platform.
- Developed modules for the Odoo enterprise management platform(Python framework), that were used internally to track company IT resources.
- Developed web application to track employee leave time using Python for backend and jQuey front-end. Setup web hosting for applications using GCP App Engine.

EDUCATION

BS, Computer Science - Computer Criminology - Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning Specialization - Stanford University & DeepLearning.Al

AWS Certified Developer - Associate - Amazon Web Services

Software Product Management Specialization - Coursera

Full Stack Web Development - Free Code Camp